A Finding Aid to the Judith Wilson Papers, 1966-2010, in the Archives of American Art AAA.wilsjudi
Archives of American Art
- Printed Material, 1981-2010; Series 7; 0.5 Linear feet Box 10
  - Magazines, 1981; 1995 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Publications Containing Judith Wilson Mentions and Citations, 1995-2004 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Interviews, 1978-2008; Series 8; 1 Linear feet Boxes 11-12
  Interviews are recorded on 97 sound cassette tapes and four CDs. Included are interviews Wilson conducted with artists, their associates, and collectors for various writing projects. Researchers should note that additional documentation on these writing projects as well as any existing interview notes can be found in Series 2: Notebooks and Series 3: Writing Projects. Also found is one interview of Wilson for StoryCorps.
  Interviews for which specific projects have been identified are grouped by project in chronological order. Other interviews are arranged alphabetically by interviewee.
  - "Alma Thomas: A One-Woman Art Movement," Ms. Magazine (Box 11)
    - Norman Lewis, 1978 June 23; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 1)
    - Harold Hart, 1978 June 27; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 2)
    - James L. Wells, 1978 June 29; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 3)
    - Sam Gilliam, 1978 June 29; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 4)
    - Jeff Donaldson, 1978 June 30; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 5)
    - Starmanda Bullock, 1978 June 30; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 6)
    - Franz Bader, 1978 June 30; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 7)
    - Adolphus Ealey, 1978 June 30; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 8)
    - Jacob and Ruth Kainen, 1978 July 1; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 9)
    - James L. Wells, 1978 July 2; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 10)
  - "Buying Art: The Big Picture," Essence (Box 11)
    - Lincoln J. Ragsdale, 1979; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 11)
    - Helen Singleton, 1979; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 12)
    - Celeste Cook, 1979; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 12)
    - Arthur Ashe, 1979; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 13)
    - Peg Alston, 1979; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 14)
    - Bobbi Dent, 1979; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 15)
    - Linda Goode-Bryant, 1979; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 16)
  - "Favorite Books," Essence (Box 11)
    - Betye Saar and Others, 1979; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 17)
  - "Howardena Pindell Makes Art That Winks At You," Ms. Magazine (Box 11)
    - Howardena Pindell, 1980 January 18; 4 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 18)
    - Howardena Pindell, 1980 February 13; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 19)
    - Richard Lerner, circa 1980 February; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 20)
  - "Ana Mendieta Plants Her Garden," Village Voice (Box 11)
    - Ana Mendieta, 1980 May 27; 3 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 21)
  - "Raymond Saunders" Unpublished Article (Box 11)
    - Raymond Saunders, 1980 June; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 22)
  - "Black Women Artists" Unpublished Article (Box 11)
    - Mary O'Neal, 1980 June; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 23)
    - Margo Humphrey, 1980 June; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 24)
    - Samella Lewis, 1980 June 30; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 25)
    - Betye Saar, 1980 July 1; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 26)
    - Senga Nengudi, 1980 July 1; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 27)
    - Suzanne Jackson, 1980 July; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 28)
    - Maren Hassinger, 1980 July 3; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 29)
  - "The Bullish Market for Black Art," Black Enterprise (Box 11)
    - Bill Pajaud, 1980 July; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 30)
  - "Edward Clark: Directions," Art in America (Box 11)
    - Ed Clark, circa 1980; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 31)
  - "Robert Colescott" Unpublished Article (Box 11)
    - Robert Colescott, 1981 February 8; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 32)
  - "Candace Hill-Montgomery" Unpublished Article (Box 11)
    - Candace Hill-Montgomery, 1981 July 21; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 33)
  - "Richard Bellamy," Issue: A Journal For Artists (Box 11)
    - Richard Bellamy, 1985 June 28; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 34)
  - "Robert Ferris Thompson," Issue: A Journal For Artists (Box 11)
    - Robert Ferris Thompson, 1985 October 10; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 35)
  - "Coming of Age: A Look at 3 Contemporary Artists," Essence (Box 11)
    - Howardena Pindell, 1986 January 25; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 36)
    - Jeanne Moutoussamy-Ashe, 1986 January 27; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 37)
    - Beverly Buchanan, 1986 January 27; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 38)
  - "Raymond Saunders," Issue: A Journal For Artists (Box 11)
    - Raymond Saunders, 1986 March 3; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 39)
  - "Hexes, Totems and Necessary Saints," Real Life (Box 11)
    - Alison Saar, 1986 March 19; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 40)
  - "In Memory of the News & Of Ourselves: The Art of Adrian Piper," Third Text (Box 11)
    - Adrian Piper, 1989 July 18; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 41)
  - "Haunted Hearts: The Use of Anti-Black Imagery in Contemporary African-American Art" Unpublished Article (Box 11)
    - Michael Ray Charles, 1997 November 4; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 42)
    - Kara Walker, 1998 January 3; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 43)
  - Other Interviews (Box 11)
    - Romare Bearden, 1983 June 17; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 44)
    - Bob Carter, 1988 November 19; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 45)
    - Ed Clark, 1983 February 12; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 46)
    - Ed Clark, 1985 April 1; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 47)
    - Ken Clay, 1987 March 26; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 48)
    - Phyllis Cooper, 1987 July 26; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 49)
    - G. C. Coxe, 1987 March 27-28; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 50)
    - Emilio Cruz, 1983 February 12; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 51)
    - R. Douglas, 1987 March 26; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 52)
    - Bob Gardner, 1990 April 14; 1990 July 9; 4 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 53)
    - Sam Gilliam, 1986 November 10; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 54)
    - Mimi Gross, 1987 March 9; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 55)
    - Charlie Haden, 1988 March 21; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 56)
    - The Holmeses, 1987 March 28; 3 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 57)
    - Ted Joans, 1986 June 6; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 58)
    - Christopher Lane, 1983 December 27; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 59)
    - Marcia Marcus, 1986 October 11; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 60)
    - Dollie and Jackie McLean, 1986 August 3; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 61)
    - Jay Milder, 1983 February 11; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 62)
    - Peter Passuntino, 1986 July 11; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 63)
    - Sonny Rollins, 1987 August 12; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 64)
    - Alison Saar, 1985 October 29; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 65)
    - Alison Saar, 1989 July 26; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 66)
    - A. B. Spellman, 1987 January 13; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 67)
    - P. Suttman, 1987 March 21; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 68)
    - Kenneth Young, 1986 November 8; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 69)
    - Mrs. Zimmerman, 1987 March 27; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Item 70)
    - Charles Rotmil, 2007 August 8; 1 Sound discs (CD) (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Judith Wilson StoryCorps Interview, 2007-2008 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Includes 2 sound discs (CD).
- Video Recordings, 1979-2007; Series 9; 4 Folders Box 12
  Found here are six DVD video recordings including video art by artists Ulysses Jenkins, Barbara McCullough, and Maren Hassinger. Also found is A Brush with Success, a 30-minute documentary film about artist Ed Clark, directed by Charles Martin.
  - Documentary, A Brush with Success, 2007; 1 Videodiscs (DVD) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Maren Hassinger, "Legacy", 2006; 1 Videodiscs (DVD) (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Ulysses Jenkins, Video Art, 1981-2006; 3 Videodiscs (DVD) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    "Inconsequential Doggereal"
    "Dream City: The Videotape"
    "Dream City: Ritual-Video-Performance"
    "Z-Grass"
    "Self Divination"
    "Mutual Native Duplex"
    "The Nomadics"
    "Planet X"
  - Barbara McCullough, "Water Ritual #1: An Urban Rite of Purification", 1979; 1 Videodiscs (DVD) (Box 12, Folder 6)